Bodky, Erwin; Papers ger023
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used by Bodky, Undated; 8
  - Books and pamphlets, Undated; 8.1
    - Funfzehntes Deutsches Bachfest, vom 28. bis 31. Mai 1927 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 3b)
    - Holz, Arno.Flordeliefe. Berlin-Wilmersdorf: A. R. Meyer, Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 4)
    - Jode, Fritz. "Lebensgestalterin Musik in der Schule". [Leipzig: Obralbruck von Oscar Brandstetter], Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 5)
    - Keller, Hermann.Die Klavierwerke Bachs. Leipzig, 1950 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 6)
    - Levarie, Siegmund.Fugue and Form, 1941 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 7)
    - De Muiderkring, Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 8)
      Opvoering van Dr. P. H. Schroder's luisterspel op 29 November 1937 in het Muiderslot als een bijdrage tot de reeks van herdenkingen van Joost van den Vondel.
    - Muller-Blattau, Joseph.Hamann & Herder in ihren Beziehungen zur Musik. Königsberg, 1931 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 9a)
    - Othmayr, Caspar M. "Reutterische und Jegerische Liedlein". Heft 2, 3, 4, 1928 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 9b)
    - Rilke, Rainer Maria.The Life of the Virgin Mary. Translation by Mrs. M. D. Herder Norton, Undated; photocopy of typescript (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 10a)
    - Rumberger, Marian S.A Conspectus of the Works of Johann Sebastian Bach, Compiled for the Bach - Gesellschaft Edition. Ann Arbor, Michigan: J. W. Edwards, 1948 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 10b)
    - Schonberg, Arnold.Gurrelieder, Undated; 2 copies (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 11a)
    - Smijers, D.Nederlandsche Muziekgeschiedenis, [1903] (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 11b)
    - Smyers, Alb. "De Polyphone Kerkmuziek van de XVe en de XVIe eeuw", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 11c)
      (from Musica Sacra, December 1936.).
    - Weber, Wilhelm.Beethoven Missa Solemnis. Augsburg, 1897 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 11d)
  - Journals, Undated; 8.2
    - Allgemeine Musikzeitung, Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 12)
      Fest-Nummer, v. 52, no. 23/24 (12. Juni 1925).
      v. 53, no. 21/22 - 21. Mai 1926.
      v. 58, no. 19/20 - 8. Mai 1931 [unidentified-issue].
    - American Musicological Society Journal, Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 13a)
      v. 1 no. 1 Spring 1948.
      v. 1 no. 2 Summer 1948.
      v. 5 no. 2 Summer 1952.
      v. 9 no. 1 Spring 1956.
    - Athenaion Blaetter, 4 Jahrgang Nr. 1, 1935 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 13b)
    - Caecilia en de Muziek, Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 13c)
      93 (10) Jahrgang, nr. 2 - December 1935.
      93 (10) Jahrgang, nr. 3 - Januari 1936.
      93 (10) Jahrgang, nr. - Februari 1936.
    - Harpsichord, Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 14)
      v. 7 no. 1 - February, March, April 1974.
      v. 7 no. 2 - May, June, July 1974.
      v. 7 no. 4 - November, December, January 1974-75.
    - Jahrbuch der Staatlichen Akademie für Kirchen - und Schulmusik Berlin, Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 15a)
      Dritter Jahrgang - 1929-1930.
      Vierter Jahrgang - 1930-1931.
      Fiffifter Jahrgang - 1931-1932.
    - Journal of Renaissance and Baroque Music, Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 15b)
      v. 1 no. I - March 1946.
      v. 1 no. 4 - June 1947.
    - Das Klavierbuch, v. 9 Heft 8/9, Oktober/November 1927 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 15c)
    - Der Kreis, Juni 1932 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 15d)
      10 Jahrgang 3. heft.
    - Melos, 2 Februar 1928 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 16a)
      7 Jahrgang Heft 2.
    - Mens en Melodie, Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 16b)
      Derde Jahrgang, Nummer 4 - April 1948.
      3e Jahrgang, no. 5 - Mai 1948.
    - Mensch en Melodie, Tweede Jahrgang, nummer 8, 1947 August (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 16c)
    - Music & Letters, v. 23 no. 4, 1942 October (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 16d)
    - Musica Viva no. 1, Avril 1936 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 17)
      (contains portrait of Busoni).
    - Die Musik, Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 18)
      v. 24 no. 2 - November 1931 (contains article by Bodky: "Das Cembalo Clavichord - Problem" - p. 97-101).
      v. 24 no. 3 - Dezember 1931 (contains article by Bodky: "Instrumentale Weihnachtsmusik" - p. 166-172.
      v. 24 no. 8 - Mai 1932 (contains article by Bodky: "Hat das Klavier in der Hausmusik noch eine Zukunft?" - p. 569-575).
    - Musikblätter des Anbruch, 8. Jahrgang, Nummer 1 - Janner - Heft, 1926 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 19a)
    - Orgaan der Federatie van Nederlandische Toonkunstenaars-Vereenigingen, Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 19b)
      2e Jahrgang no. 10 - Juli 1936 (contains article by Bodky: "De Kunst van het Continuo-Spel en Haar Beteekenis voor het Begnijpen der 'Oude Muziek'" - p. 233-237.
      2e Jahrgang; no. 11/12 - Augustus/September 1936 (contains article by Bodky: "De Kunst van het Continuo-Spel... (Slot)" - p. 254-258.
    - S.I.M., 8 année no. 11, 1912 November (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 20a)
    - Signale für die musikalische Welt, 80. Jahrgang no. 7, 15. Februar 1922 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 20b)
      (contains picture of Bodky opposite p. 156, and mention on p. 238).
    - De Wereld der Muziek, 5e Jahrgang no. 1, 1938 October (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 21a)
      (contains article by Bodky: "Het Clavecymbel en de Herllving der 'Oude Muziek'" - p. 1-12).
    - Zeitschrift für Hausmusik, 5 Jahrgang, Heft 4, Juli/August 1936 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 21b)
    - Zeitschrift Or Musik, 94 Jahrgang Heft 7/8, Juli/August 1927 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 21c)
  - Offprints, Undated; 8.3
    - Apel, Willi. "Die Fuge: Funf Vortrage mit Musikbeispielen", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 22a)
      (from Deutsche Welle, Winter 1931/32).
    - Bodky, Erwin. "New Contributions to the Problem of the Interpretation of Bach's Keyboard Works", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 22b)
      (from Kongress-Bericht Internationale Gesellschaft für Musikwissenschaft, 1952).
    - Bodky, Erwin. "Wege und Ziele des Klavierunterrichts an der Akademie", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 22c)
      (from II).
    - Bodky, Erwin. "Eckert, Heinrich. Norbert Burgmuller... (Book review), Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 22d)
    - Boyce, Banjamin. "News from Hell", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 22e)
      (from PfLA v.-58 no. 3 June 1943).
    - Bukofzer, Manfred F. "On the Performance of Renaissance Music", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 22f)
      (from the Volume of Proceedings of the Music Teachers National Association for 1941).
    - Cramer, Frederick H. "Demosthenes Redivivus", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 23a)
      (from Foreign Affairs, April 1941).
    - Falkenfeld, Hellmuth. "Kant und Kleist", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 23b)
      (from Logos v. 8 Heft 3, 1919).
    - Gal, Hans. "Theory and Practice in Composition", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 23c)
      (from Music & Letters v. 23 no. 1 January 1942).
    - Gombosi, Otto. "Studien zur Tonartenlehre des frühen Mittelalters. II & III", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 23d)
    - Hess, Albert G. "Observations on 'The Lamenting Voice of the Hidden Love'", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 23e)
      (from Journal of the American Musicological Society).
    - Heuss, Alfred. "Bachs 'Kunst der Fuge'", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 24)
    - Hibberd, Lloyd. "Estampie and Stantipes", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 25a)
      (from Speculum v. 19 no. 2 April 1944).
    - Kestenberg, Leo. "Die Gesellscraft für Musikerziehung in. Prag...", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 25b)
      (from Prager Runschau, Jahrgang v. 1, nr. 3 [1936]).
    - Kestenberg, Leo. "Die Internationale Zentralstelle für Musikerziehung in Prag", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 25c)
      (from Der Auftakt; XVI Jahrg. Nr. 5-6, 1936).
    - Klages, Ludwig. "Dichtungen von Ludwig Klages" (ersebienen in der 2. bis 5. folge der Blatter für die Kinst), Undated; typescript (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 26a)
    - Lang, Paul H. "Schrade, Leo.Beethoven in France. The Growth of an Idea", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 26b)
      (Book review) (from The Romanic Review, February 1944) (See reply by Schrade).
    - Levy, Kenneth Jay. "Vaudeville, Vers Mesurés et Airs de Cour", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 26c)
      (from Colloques Internationaux du Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, 1954).
    - Lipmann, Otto. "Über Begriff und Formen der Intelligenz", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 27)
      (from Zeitschrift angewandte Psychologie, v. 24, no. 3/4, 1924).
    - Lowinsky, Edward E. "The Goddess Fortuna in Music...", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 28a)
      (from The Musical Quarterly v. 29 no. 1, January 1943).
    - Moser, Hans Joachim. "Carl Maria von Weber", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 28b)
      (from Die Grossen Deutschen, III 1956).
    - Moser, Hans Joachim. "Zwischen Schütz und Bach", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 28c)
      (from Wissenschaftliche Zeitschrift der Karl Marx - Universität, 4. Jahrgang 5).
    - Nathan, Hans. "The Career of a Revival Hymn", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 29a)
      (from Southern Folklore Quarterly v. 7 no. 2, June 1943).
    - Nathan, Hans. "Walt Whitman and the Marine Band", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 29b)
      (from More Books: The Bulletin of the Boston Public Library, February 1943).
    - Plamenac, Dragan. "An Unknown Violin Tablature of the Early 17th Century", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 30)
      (from the Papers of the American Musicological Society, Annual Meeting, 1941).
    - Schrade, Leo. "On Beethoven in France", Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 31)
      (Reply to review by Paul Lang, which see) (from The Romanic Review, February 1945).
- Catalogs, advertisements, etc., Undated; 9
  - American Institute-of Musicology.Ten Years of Musica Disciplina: A Journal of the History of Music, 1946-1956 (Box 4 (9-Catalogs, advertisements, etc.), Folder 32a)
  - Archiv Produktion.Katalog 1957, Undated (Box 4 (9-Catalogs, advertisements, etc.), Folder 32b)
  - Broude Brothers.Catalogue No.46: Music and Musical Literature, Undated (Box 4 (9-Catalogs, advertisements, etc.), Folder 32c)
  - Broude Brothers.Catalogue No. 50 New And Current Vocal Works, Undated (Box 4 (9-Catalogs, advertisements, etc.), Folder 32d)
  - Gamble's Annual Catalog of Supplies 1949-1950, Undated (Box 4 (9-Catalogs, advertisements, etc.), Folder 32e)
  - Ganley, Eric H.Catalogue of Music & Books on Music, Undated (Box 4 (9-Catalogs, advertisements, etc.), Folder 33a)
    No. 1, 1949; no. 10, 1952; no. 27, 1958.
  - Mummery, Kenneth.A Catalogue of Music and Books on Music, 1954 (Box 4 (9-Catalogs, advertisements, etc.), Folder 33b)
  - Peters (C. F.) Corporation.Chamber Music (catalog), 1955 (Box 4 (9-Catalogs, advertisements, etc.), Folder 34a)
  - Scientific Library Service.Music Catalogue No. 24, 1955 Fall (Box 4 (9-Catalogs, advertisements, etc.), Folder 34b)
  - Société Internationale de Musicologie. (Program) Ve Congrès, 3 au 7 juillet 1952 (Box 4 (9-Catalogs, advertisements, etc.), Folder 34c)
  - Verslag Omtrent den Toestand der Maatschappij Tot Bevordering der Toonkunst..., 1933-1934 (Box 4 (9-Catalogs, advertisements, etc.), Folder 34d)
    (See reference to Bodky on p. 18).